<resources>

    <string name="app_name">POSH APP</string>
>>>>>>> d427a11d0285c4def8dd25c66e269bd78d86b985

    <!--notes-->
    <string name="definition">
        A business model in which a distributor network is needed to build the
        business. Usually such businesses are also multilevel marketing in nature in that payouts
        occur at more than one level. "\n\n"Network marketing is a type of business opportunity that is very popular with people looking
        for part-time, flexible businesses. Some of the best-known companies in America, including
        Avon, Mary Kay Cosmetics, Rain International and Tupperware, fall under the network
        marketing umbrella. "\n\n"

        Network marketing programs feature a low upfront investment-usually only a few hundred
        dollars for the purchase of a product sample kit-and the opportunity to sell a product line
        directly to friend, family and other personal contacts. Most network marketing programs also ask
        participants to recruit other sales representatives. The recruits constitute a reps downline, and
        their sales generate income for those above them in the program."\n\n"

        Things can get sticky when a network marketing network compensates participants primarily for
        recruiting others rather than for selling the companys products or services. A network marketing
        system in which most of the revenue comes from recruitment may be considered an illegal
        pyramid scheme."\n\n"

        Since network marketing programs are usually exempt from business opportunity regulation and
        arent defined as franchises under state and federal franchise laws, youll need to do your own
        investigation before investing any money."\n\n"

    </string>

    <string name="mlm_and_pyramid_schemes">
        Multilevel Marketing (MLM) and Pyramid Schemes Can Be Very Similar"\n"
        Considering a multilevel marketing opportunity (MLM)? Be careful. It may well be a
        legitimate multilevel marketing business. Or it may be a pyramid scheme - an illegal scam
        designed to steal your money. This article explains the difference between MLM and pyramid
        schemes so you can distinguish between them.

        Multilevel Marketing Can Be a Good Thing"\n"
        Multilevel marketing (MLM) is an attractive business proposition to many people. It offers the
        opportunity to become involved in a system for distributing products to consumers. Unlike the
        person starting a business from scratch, the MLM participant has the support of a direct
        selling company that supplies the products and sometimes offers training as well.

        HOW THE MLM WORKS"\n"
        As a MLM consultant or contractor or distributor (different companies call them different
        things) you make your money by selling the products to other multilevel marketing participants.
        If they are not already a member of your MLM Company, you sign them up."\n\n"Besides earning money off your own sales, you also earn a percentage of the income generated
        by the distributors that you have brought into the program (these are known as your downline).
        Often there are bonuses for selling particular amounts of product or signing up a certain number
        of new members; you can earn cars and trips as well as cash. Sounds good, does not it? And being
        part of a well-run MLM business can be a lot like being a member of a large extended family.

        PYRAMID SCHEMES"\n"
        Unfortunately, not every multilevel marketing opportunity is a legitimate business opportunity.
        Many pyramid schemes, frauds designed to part the unwary from their money, are disguised.

        Like multilevel marketing, pyramid schemes depend on recruiting people to become
        distributors of a product or service. Like MLM, the pyramid scheme offers the opportunity to
        make money by signing up more recruits and by accomplishing certain levels of achievement.

        The big difference between multilevel marketing and pyramid schemes is that MLM is legal
        in Canada (and most of the US) and pyramid schemes are not. Participating in a pyramid scheme
        is an offense under the Criminal Code of Canada, punishable by up to five years imprisonment.

        But it can be very difficult for the person looking for a business opportunity to tell the difference
        between a legitimate MLM opportunity and a pyramid scheme at a glance. How do you tell
        whether it is a legitimate business opportunity or a scam?

        Unlike MLM, Pyramid Schemes Have Only One Purpose
        The big difference between MLM and a pyramid scheme is in the way the business operates.
        The entire purpose of a pyramid scheme is to get your money and then use you to recruit other
        suckers (ahem - distributors).

        The entire purpose of MLM is to move product. The theory behind MLM is that the larger the
        network of distributors, the more product the business will be able to sell.

        Use these questions as an acid test if youre in the least doubt as to whether the opportunity
        youre considering is multilevel marketing or a pyramid scheme:

        Checklist for Recognizing a Pyramid Scheme:
        Are you required to invest a large amount of money up front to become a distributor? This
                        investment request may be disguised as an inventory charge. Legitimate MLM businesses do not
                        require large startup costs.

                        Are you required to "invest" a large amount of money up front to become a distributor? Legitimate MLM companies will offer and stick to inventory buy-backs for at least 80% of what you paid.

                        Is there any mention of or attention paid to a market for the product or service?Multilevel marketing depends on establishing a market for the companys products. If the company doesnt
                        seem to have any interest in consumer demand for its products, dont sign up.

                        Is there more emphasis on recruitment than on selling the product or service? Remember, the
                        difference between multilevel marketing and a pyramid scheme is in the focus. The pyramid scheme focuses on fast profits from signing people up and getting their money. If recruitment seems to be the focus of the plan, run.

              These next two questions will help you determine what the focus of the company is:

                        Is the plan designed so that you make more money by recruiting new members rather than through sales that you make yourself? This is the signature of a pyramid scheme operation.

                        Are you offered commissions for recruiting new members?Another pyramid scheme trademark. Its the number of people who are willing to sign up that matter in a pyramid scheme, not the products or services being offered.


    Pyramid Scheme vs. MLM: How to Protect Yourself
    As always, when youre investigating a potential business opportunity, youll want to gather all
        the information you can about the MLM Company‘s products and operations.

    Get (and read) written copies of the companys sales literature, business plan and/or marketing
    plan.


    Talk to other people who have experience with the multilevel marketing company and the
    products to determine whether the products are actually being sold and if they are of high
    quality.


    Check with the Better Business Bureau to see if there have been any complaints about the
    company.


    And listen carefully when youre at that MLM recruitment meeting. Inflated claims for the
    amazing amounts of money youre going to make should set your alarm bells ringing.


    Being part of a successful multilevel marketing company can be both profitable and fun, but
    unfortunately, some purported MLM opportunities are actually just cons designed to flatten
    both your wallet and your dream of running a business.

        Better Alternatives to MLMs
If you are looking to start a full or part-time business, there are many other proven business
ideas that are alternatives to MLMs


Is Network Marketing a Good Career?
Network marketing is a good career for a select few. It will be a waste for most others. As with any business, a successful multi-level marketing (MLM) venture will require a significant investment of time and effort. Done correctly, it‘s a great way to build wealth. But there‘s no room for people who think they can make a quick buck with it.

    </string>

    <string name="network_marketing">
        Network marketing is a referral-based sales business. A company will offer a product or a service and recruit others to sell it for them. Sales reps, who are independent contractors and not employees, are paid commissions for what they sell. If they recruit other reps, then they‘ll also earn a portion of their sales, too.


    As a basic example, let‘s imagine that a company uses an MLM model to sell laptops. You might join because for each one you sell, you‘ll earn a 10% commission. If you recruit me into the business, you‘d also earn a 2% commission on each laptop I sell. And if I recruit someone else, you‘d earn 0.5% on each one they sell, and so on.

    Rain International
    Juenesse Global
    Herbalife
    Mary Kay

    Primerica
    Nu Skin
    ACN



What are the advantages of MLM?
The greatest advantage of multi-level marketing is that you can build a thriving business without having to develop a product or a brand. The company provides it for you; all you need to do is selling. A well-managed firm will have systems and marketing material available to bolster your chances of success.

    It‘s also scalable. You can develop your business into a vast enterprise with numerous layers of recruits. If you‘re willing to invest the time, eventually you can have enough sales reps on your
    team to walk away from it altogether. A network marketing venture can thus be an effective income producing asset. There are plenty of MLM entrepreneurs who earn six and seven-figure incomes passively.

    Further, MLM is a great way to develop sales, public speaking, leadership and management skills. I often suggest it to aspiring entrepreneurs who haven‘t yet decided what they want to pursue. Network marketing may not make you rich overnight, but it can teach much of what you need to know to have a successful business. You can use it as a training ground.

    Lastly, a lot of people find value from the mentorship and personal develop components involved in network marketing. If you participate in MLM, you‘ll join a community of like-minded others. Your peers will want to reach financial freedom, they‘ll stand by their product, they‘ll believe in their mission and they want to expand their skillset. That‘s valuable in and of itself.


    Are there downsides to network
Yes – and they are plentiful. You should be aware of them before proceeding.
Scams
The MLM world is a hotbed for scams and shady characters. Companies like Business in Motion were found to be Ponzi schemes. Karatbars international, OneCoin, MMM and several others have all had run-ins with the authorities. In December 2016, Vemma paid a $238 million settlement to the US Federal Trade Commission (FTC) for non-compliance issues. I‘d suggest reading sites like BehindMLM.com and ThompsonBurton.com to keep abreast of current events

Changing regulatory framework
Trade and securities regulators have pushed network marketing companies to base their compensation models on sales commissions, rather than on recruitment. They take issue with firms who pay people to simply find others to join instead of actually selling the product (Vemma, for instance). It‘s likely that regulators will continue to scrutinize the MLM
Your asset can disappear
 the company folds or terminates its relationship with you that will destroy the asset you spent years building. MLM participants are reliant on the good standing of the company. One way to hedge against that risk to is to maintain close relationships with those in your downline. They would then be more likely to come with you if you choose to switch businesses.


    Most network marketing businesses come with some sort of fee to join. It will usually be in the form of a minimum monthly product purchase, a start-up fee or an annual membership expense. Moreover, there are often incentives to pay more in order to upgrade or qualify for higher bonuses.


    You could also look at it from a different perspective, though. Most small businesses come with start-up costs. Paying a few hundred or a few thousand dollars to participate is cheaper than a lot of other ventures.

    Note: an MLM company should never use the word “investment.” That would imply the distribution of securities and likely poor grasp of the law. If you are asked to invest in a network marketing business, run for the hills. MLM is a business opportunity, not an investment opportunity. Aside from the legal distinctions, one is passive while the other is active. They are not interchangeable terms.


Is network marketing a good career?
Network marketing can be a great career, contingent on a few factors. They include

The effort you make
Most people become disillusioned with network marketing because they expect to make money quickly. After a few months of dismal results, they either quit or become inactive. Even worse, they often write off the experience as a scam. To be clear: MLM is a small business. Just like any other entrepreneur, you‘ve got to work hard for years before you‘ll see results. If that‘s not an option, then network marketing (and business in general) is not right for you.

div class="finding
Finding the right company
There are a lot of MLM junkies; people who hop from one network marketing firm to the next. They abandon the former each time a shiny new business opportunity arises. Frequently jumping ship will preclude you from spending enough time on your venture. You‘ve got to find the right firm and stick with it. As part of your due diligence, you should consider:

     hidden costs
    The compensation plan (is it lucrative? Is it sales-based or recruitment-based?)
    Legal or compliance issues

While researching prospective companies, you‘ll probably find websites that call them scams. I‘ve never seen an MLM business without bad press online. There will always be someone who says they were ripped off. In my opinion, you should base your conclusions on evidence. Sometimes, where there‘s smoke there‘s fire. Other times, however, people are either disgruntled or they‘re trying to drive traffic to their own network marketing venture. Don‘t ignore what you read online, but strive to understand the context in which it was written.


Your tolerance for volatility
Income in any business is never stable, nor is it guaranteed. As an early MLM entrepreneur, you may experience months of decent earnings followed by droughts. The business won‘t produce reliable passive income for at least a few years. Such volatility can be stressful and emotionally draining, especially for those with high expenses. You should be prepared for earnings swings and manage the money you do make carefully.

How you spend your earnings
It‘s common to spend your network marketing earnings on upgrades and training packages. The company will often encourage you to do so, justifying it as an “investment in yourself.” While there‘s truth to that, people often go overboard. They‘ll dump most of what they make right back into the firm, leaving little for themselves. Doing that too often can dry you out.

As a rule of thumb, you should try to invest in activities that will directly produce revenue. For example, if you spend $200 at a hotel to host a recruitment seminar, you might make $1,000 from it. That‘s opposed to spending $200 on sales training and justifying it by saying, “Well, the skills I develop will be worth it.” Continually purchasing programs and activities that have indirect potential can be a dangerous
Conclusion
Network marketing can be a good career to pursue. You can do quite well if you build a team of hard-working individuals. The passive income that can be produced is vast. It is certainly a vehicle to reach financial

LM has pitfalls. Perhaps the main one is people being convinced that it will lead to easy money and then discovering the truth afterwards. If you make an informed decision and work hard towards success, then I‘d encourage it. If you can‘t commit to that, though, look elsewhere for opportunities.
    </string>

    <string name="start_network_marketing">
STEP 1: KNOW YOUR WHY
To be successful in any business, one must first have a dream. Your first step is to determine the WHY. Why do you want to enter network marketing? Is it because you want to be recognized? May be you want to live rich life? A car or a house? Education of your children? You must have a dream to keep you going. Also, ask yourself whether you are ready to commit to it, even if it is one hour a day! In bold, write down your dream.
>ACTIONS — WRITE YOUR TOP FIVE DREAMS THAT YOU WISH TO FULFILL WITH THIS BUSINESS.

iSTEP 2: DECIDE A GOAL
Each step is going to build a great foundation to your network marketing business. Now that you know why you want to get in network marketing, the second question is how. With help of this guide and your upline (recruiter), decide long term, yearly and monthly goals.
For example,
    Longterm goal — earn Rs. 1, 00,000 a month by 2019
Yearly goal — 2017 — earn my first 30,000
Monthly goal— recruit and train 5 new leads.

    A goal will help you stay focused and a plan will tell your brain what is needed to be done to reach that goal
    ACTION — WRITE DOWN GOALS ON A PAPER AND DISPLAY IT WHERE YOU CAN SEE IT EVERY SINGLE DAY.

STEP 3: TAKE TRAININGS OFFERED BY YOUR COMPANY AND LEADER>
The company you are working with knows the best way to become successful in that business. Thus, follow their training program and learn various tactics to form a successful customer base. Most of the good MLM companies will have excellent training program. This is where choosing a good leader is worth an effort. If you have a good leader, you will have a person to look upon, a mentor to help you grow, and a friend to celebrate small victories together!
    ACTION — ATTEND COMPANY TRAININGS AND LEARN REQUIRED SKILLS


STEP 4: MAKE A KILLER ACTION PLAN
After you have mastered the how-to‘s of business, it‘s time to put goals to action. Based on your dream, goals and trainings, plan your calendar. Create a weekly task list of the month and share it with your Downline/ team members. Remember, in network marketing business, the more your team members grow, the better. Your whole action plan must focus on 1. Team members and 2. New personal recruits. You are a leader and you are responsible for the growth of your team.
    ACTION — CREATE A MONTHLY CALENDER OF TASKS FOR SELF AND TEAM MEMBERS.

STEP 5: PLAN TO ACTION
    Most of the people stop after planning, successful people converts their plans into reality. While 80% will give up after planning, be a leader and put your effort to convert your dream into reality. Your monthly goals should include:
    1. Sales of minimum required order
    2. Recruiting new team members
    3. Training existing team members
    This is all you have to keep in mind. All your campaigns must revolve around these three important goals. Here on this blog, you will find how to achieve success in each of these goals, so stay tuned.
    ACTION — PUT YOURSELVES OUT THERE AND GENERATES POTENTIAL LEADS, TRAIN TEAM MEMBERS.

STEP 6: REVIEW YOUR ACTIONS
At the end of each week or month, reflect on what you have achieved, the opportunities you have missed, and what can be improved. Celebrate your victory with team members and learn from the mistakes you made this month. Progress check session can tell you whether you are going to be successful or not, how close are you towards your goal and prepare you to generate affective action plans for the next month.
    ACTION — CREATE A MONTHLY CALENDER OF TASKS FOR SELF AND TEAM MEMBERS.



A journey starts with the first step.
SUCCESS FORMULA à DREAM — GOALS — TRAINING — PLAN — ACTION — REVIEW.
    You have your guide to start network marketing. Now all you have to do is find your motivation and start putting plans to actions. In no time, you will start seeing the fruits of your effort. Network marketing is an excellent opportunity for a person who wants stable, ever increasing income while being your own boss.

    Join us or tell others to download POSH APP to receive more amazing information’s and guides like this and many other more. Until then, stay blessed.

Can you make money from network marketing
Multi-level marketing, sometimes referred to as network marketing, companies typically give you several ways to earn. First, you can profit by marketing the companys products to
others. You can also use the products yourself and essentially become your own customer. Finally, you can recruit others.

    </string>

    <string name="scam_or_slam_dunk">

I recently accepted a friend‘s invite for an evening get-together. As soon as I arrived, I realized I wasn‘t coming over for the usual conversation and cocktails. “I have this amazing opportunity to share with you!” she said enthusiastically.


    The opportunity turned out to be a multi-level marketing presentation for a company that provides satellite services and utilities. I could earn money by simply signing up friends and relatives for services they used anyway. But if I really wanted to make money, I could recruit them to become company representatives underneath me and earn a percentage of their sales, on top what I‘d earn from mine.


    Not surprisingly, the presentation ignited a firestorm within our circle of friends between those who saw it as an opportunity and those who didn‘t.

    This debate isn’t a new one. Here are the arguments for and against multi-level marketing.


What is Multi-Level Marketing?>
Contrary to what some people think, multi-level marketing is not a pyramid scheme.


    In a pyramid scheme, you earn money by bringing in people underneath you, not by selling a product. As long as a company has a product available for sale to the general public, it’s a legitimate business, according to the Federal Trade Commission‘s 1979 ruling on Amway. (Here’s more information on what the FTC considers multi-level marketing.)


    Multi-level marketing, sometimes referred to as network marketing, companies typically give you several ways to earn.


    First, you can profit by marketing the company’s products to others. You can also use the products yourself and essentially become your own customer. Finally, you can recruit others. Most multi-level marketing companies give you a percentage of whatever sales those underneath you make. With each level that comes in underneath you, you earn a higher percentage of the sale‘s profit.


    Again, it is not a pyramid scheme, because your earnings are based on the sale of actual products.<p>

The Argument for Multi-level Marketing
According to its proponents, if you want to ditch your 9-to-5 job, start your own business or become your own boss, multi-level marketing is one of the cheapest and easiest ways to do so.

    You may have to invest money in products to show to potential customers, or pay a sign-up fee (my friend’s company required a $500 fee to get started).

    However, when you consider what it costs to open other types of businesses, a few hundred dollars isn‘t much.


    “If you were purchasing a small business like a Subway franchise, the initial outlay would be over $100,000, and you would need a networth of $500,000 to be approved,” says Garrett Sanders, who operates his own network marketing business in North Carolina.


“How long would it take to recoup that investment?”


    Multi-level marketing also has a built-in mentorship program. The people who recruit you have a vested (financial) interest in seeing you succeed.


    Not only will those above you help you with presentations and answer questions, but most companies offer regular meetings with your peers to discuss strategies, motivational programs and additional training resources.


    With hard work, you can make money, but how much depends on the company you work with and the product. It’s extremely unlikely you’ll make an extraordinary amount of money overnight.

    Surprisingly, money isn‘t the only reason people become involved with multi-level marketing businesses. Many people, especially stay-at-home parents and retirees, use their businesses to get out of the house, meet new people, learn new skills and do something that gives them a sense of accomplishment.</p>


The Argument against Multi-level Marketing
Jon M. Taylor knows firsthand how multi-level marketing works. After a successful sales career, first selling encyclopedias and then insurance, he decided to give multi-level marketing a try. He threw himself into a multi-level marketing program, rose to the “level of about the top 1% of distributors”… and still didn’t turn a profit. Taylor, an industry expert who runs the website MLM-theTruth.com, says multi-level marketing is designed so profits flow up. More than 99% of people who get involved with multi-level marketing programs don‘t earn a profit, according to his research. In addition, many don’t even make enough money to cover their expenses, which can include purchasing products, paying membership dues and traveling to events.


    But there are other, non-financial reasons to avoid multi-level marketing programs, he says.


    One is the toll they can take on personal relationships. When she realized their friends and family were avoiding them, Taylor‘s wife told him it was her or the program. Another is the emotional challenge. Recruits are often told if they follow the program, they‘ll turn a profit, Taylor says.

    When they don‘t succeed, they‘re told it‘s because they‘re doing something wrong, even though he contends the products are usually overpriced and inferior to what is available elsewhere



The Bottom Line
If you‘re a considering signing up for a multi-level marketing program, ask questions. Find out about the product and get the company‘s refund policy in writing.

    The FTC provides guidance on how to steer clear of pyramid schemes and fraudulent businesses.

Your Turn:What do you think about multi-level marketing? If you’ve tried it, we’d love to hear your stories in the comments.


    </string>

    <string name="business_model">

        A business model describes the rationale of how an organization creates, delivers, and captures value, in economic, social, cultural or other contexts. The process of business model construction and modification is also called business model innovation and forms a part of business strategy.


What is a Business Model?
    A Business Model is a conceptual structure that supports the viability of a product or company and explains how the company operates, makes money, and how it intends to achieve its goals. All the business processes and policies that a company adopts and follows are part of the business model.


According to management guru Peter Drucker:
    A business model is supposed to answer who your customer is, what value you can create/add for the customer and how you can do that at reasonable costs.


    Thus a business model is a description of the rationale of how a company creates, delivers and captures value for itself as well as the customer.


    The widespread use of business models came into existence with the advent of the personal computer which let people test and model the different components of a business. Successful business models before that were mostly created by accident and not by design. It‘s different for business plans and business strategies though.



Every business model intrinsically has three parts
Everything related to designing and manufacturing the product
Everything related to selling the product, from finding the right customers to distributing the product
Everything related to how the customer will pay and how the company will make money




Different Types of Business Models
      There are different types of business models meant for different businesses. Some of the basic types of business models are:

Manufacturer
A manufacturer makes finished products from raw materials. It may sell directly to the customers or sell it to a middleman i.e. another business that sells it finally to the customer. Ex: Ford, 3M, General Electric.

Distributor
A distributor buys products from manufacturers and resells them to the retailers or the public. Ex: Auto Dealerships.

Retailer
A retailer sells directly to the public after purchasing the products from a distributor or wholesaler. Ex: Amazon, Tesco.

Franchise
A franchise can be a manufacturer, distributor or retailer. Instead of creating a new product, the franchisee uses the parent business‘s model and brand while paying royalties to it. Ex: McDonald’s, Pizza Hut.


Brick-and-mortar
Brick-and-mortar is a traditional business model where the retailers, wholesalers, and manufacturers deal with the customers face-to-face in an office, a shop, or a store that the business owns or rents.


eCommerce
E-Commerce business model is an upgradation of the traditional brick-and-mortar business model. It focuses on selling products by creating a web-store on the internet.


Bricks-and-clicks
A company that has both an online and offline presence allows customers to pick up products from the physical stores while they can place the order online. This model gives flexibility to the business since it is present online for customers who live in areas where they do not have brick-and-mortar stores. Ex: Almost all apparel companies nowadays.


Nickel-and-dime
In this model, the basic product provided to the customers is very cost-sensitive and hence priced as low as possible. For every other service that comes with it, a certain amount is charged. Ex: All low-cost air carriers.


Bricks-and-clicks A company that has both an online and offline presence allows customers to pick up products from the physical stores while they can place the order online. This model gives flexibility to the business since it is present online for customers who live in areas where they do not have brick-and-mortar stores. Ex: Almost all apparel companies nowadays.


Freemium
This is one of the most common business models on the Internet. Companies offer basic services to the customers for free while charging a certain premium for extra add-ons. So there will be multiple plans with various benefits for different customers. Generally, the basic service comes with certain restrictions or limitations, such as in-app advertisements, storage restrictions etc., which the premium plans shall not have. For example, the basic version of Dropbox comes with 2 GB storage. If you want to increase that limit, you can move to the Pro plan and pay a premium of $9.99 a month for it. Some online image editors allow you to edit only a certain number of images in the free basic plan while an unlimited number of images in the paid plan. YouTube’s free plan comes with ads while the premium (Red) plan has no ad interruption plus it has other benefits too. This model is one of the most adopted models for online companies because it is not only a great marketing tool but also a cost-effective way to scale up and attract new users.


Subscription
If customer acquisition costs are high, this business model might be the most suitable option. The subscription business model lets you keep customers over a long-term contract and get recurring revenues from them through repeat purchases. Ex: Netflix, Dollar Shave Club.


Aggregator
Aggregator business model is a recently developed model where the company various service providers of a niche and sell their services under its own brand. The money is earned as commissions. Ex. Uber, Airbnb, Oyo.


Online Marketplace
Online marketplaces aggregate different sellers into one platform who then compete with each other to provide the same product/service at competitive prices. The marketplace builds its brand over different factors like trust, free and/or on-time home delivery, quality sellers, etc. and earns commission on every sale carried on its platform. Ex. Amazon, Alibaba.


Advertisement
Advertisement business models are evolving even more with the rise of the demand for free products and services on the internet. Just like the earlier times, these business models are popular with media publishers like YouTube, Forbes, etc. where the information is provided for free but are accompanied with advertisements which are paid for by identified sponsors.


Data Licensing / Data Selling
With the advent of the internet, there has been an increase in the amount of data generated upon the users‘ activities over the internet. This has led to the advent of a new business model – the data licensing business model. Many companies like Twitter and One signal sell or license the data of its users or users of users to third parties which then use the same for analysis, advertising, and other purposes.


Agency-Based
An agency can be considered as a partner company which specialises in handling the non-core business activities like advertising, digital marketing, PR, ORM, etc. This company partners with several other companies that outsource their non-core tasks to them and is responsible to maintain privacy and efficiency in their work. Examples of such agencies are Ogilvy and Mathers, Dentsu Aegis Network, etc.


Affiliate Marketing
Affiliate marketing business model is a commission-based model where the affiliate builds its business around promoting a partner‘s product and directs all its efforts to convince its followers and users to buy the same. In return, the affiliate gets a commission for every sale referred. An example of a business operating on affiliate marketing business model is lifewire.com.


Dropshipping
Dropshipping is a type of e-commerce business model where the business owns no product or inventory but just a store. The actual product is sold by partner sellers who receive the order as soon as the store receives an order from the ultimate customer. These partner sellers then deliver the products directly to the customer.


Crowdsourcing
Crowdsourcing business model involves the users to contribute to the value provided. This business model is often combined with other business and revenue models to create an ultimate solution for the user and to earn money. Examples of businesses using crowdsourcing business model are Wikipedia, reCAPTCHA, Duolingo, etc.


Peer 2 Peer Catalyst/Platform
A P2P economy is a decentralized internet-based economy where two parties interact directly with each other to buy or sell goods or to conduct a transaction without the intervention of any third party. A P2P catalyst is a platform where these users meet. Examples of P2P platforms are Craigslist, OLX, Airbnb etc.


Blockchain


SAAS, IAAS, PAAS
Many companies have started offering their software, platform, and infrastructure as a service. The ‗as a service‘ business model works on the principle of pay as you go where the customer pays for his usage of such software, platform, and infrastructure; he pays for what and how many features he has used and not for what he hasn‘t.


High Touch
The High Touch model is one which requires lots of human interaction. The relationship between the salesperson and the customer has a huge impact on the overall revenues of the company. The companies with this business model operate on trust and credibility. Ex: Hair salons, consulting firms.


Low Touch
The opposite of the High Touch model, the Low Touch model requires minimal human assistance or intervention in selling a product or service. Since as a company, you do not have to maintain a huge sales force, your costs decrease, though such companies also focus on improving technology to further reduce human intervention while making the customer experience better at the same time. Ex: IKEA, Survey Monkey.


    Of course, most companies do not operate on any one of these business models but rather on a combination of some. Like it is perfectly possible for you to be a Bricks-and-clicks Low Touch Retailer or a High Touch Subscription-Based Manufacturer. What business model you choose depends on your business needs and what value you want to create for your stakeholders. Next, we will see how to develop the perfect business model for your startup, so that the chances of your success are amplified.

    </string>

    <string name="startup_process">

            We know how important your dream business is to you. Therefore, we‘ve come up with an all in one guide: The Startup Process to help you turn your vision into reality.

        10 MOST COMMON BUSINESS MODELS TO MAKE A PROFIT
    One of the most critical elements of any sustainable business is achieving a positive cash-flow. Without that, even the best intentions will fail.
        By Martin Zwilling Founder and CEO, Startup Professionals


    I was mentoring some graduate students at a local university recently, and I sensed that profit seems to be a dirty word these days to many aspiring entrepreneurs. Im certainly not a fan of customer rip-offs, but even non-profits have to be cash-flow positive, or have deep pockets, to help anyone for long. Every business needs to develop a revenue model even before a product.


    The alternatives range from giving the product away for free (revenue from ads), to pricing based on costs, to charging what the market will bear (premium pricing). The implications of the decision you make are huge, including brand image, funding requirements, and long-term business viability.


    Its naïve to think you can sell below costs, and make it up by attracting more customers.


    This may seem like Business Fundamentals 101, but the market changes rapidly, so I thought it might be useful to share what I see as the most common revenue models being used by businesses today.


    As an experienced business advisor, here is my current summary, with some of the pros and cons or special considerations for each:


Product is free, revenue is from advertisers.
This is the most common model used by online businesses and apps today, the so-called Facebook model, where your service is free, and the revenue comes from advertising.
The challenge is to get the first million customers, before advertisers will sign up. Facebook spent $150 million getting started.


Freemium model - people pay for upgrade.
In this variation on the free model, used by LinkedIn and many other online and app offerings, the basic function is free, but premium services are only available for an additional fee.
This also requires a base critical mass, and real work to differentiate and convert users to paying customers.

Price based on product costs plus margin.
In this more traditional product pricing model, the price is set at two to five times the product cost to cover overhead and operational expenses.
If your product is a commodity, the margin may be as thin as ten percent. Use it when your new technology gives you a tremendous cost improvement.

Price based on average value to customer
If you can quantify a large value or cost savings to the customer, greater than your cost, charge a price commensurate with the value delivered. This doesnt work well with "nice to have" an offering, like social networks, but does work for new drugs and medical devices that solve critical health problems.


Price with recurring low subscription payments
This is a very popular model today for Internet services, with monthly or yearly payments, in lieu of one higher up-front price.

Advantages for your business include a stable revenue stream, customer retention, and increasing customer investment over time. The customer advantage is a lower entry cost.


Tiered pricing based on volume on customer scope
In product environments, where an enterprise product may have one user or hundreds of thousands, a common approach is to price by user ranges, or volume usage limits.

Keep the number of tiers small for manageability. This approach doesnt typically apply to consumer products and services.

    Revenue is a percentage of every transaction.
This is another popular model for platforms, e-commerce, and affiliates, where you as the transaction or product provider get a small percentage or royalty on every ultimate sale to customers by others. Amazon led the way on this one online, but distributors have long used this model in retail


Low product price, but support is extra
In this model, the product price is attractive or free, but the customers are charged for installation, customization, training and other services.

This model is good for getting your foot in the door, but it is basically a services business with the product as a marketing cost. Customers generally dislike this model.


Low entry price, with priced features additional
This approach works if your product can be configured "bare-bones" for a low price, and additional features priced separately.

It is a very competitive approach, but requires design and development effort for value at every level. Expect extra costs for development, testing, documentation, and support.


Low price base, make money on disposables
With this model, popularly called the razor-blade model, the base unit is often sold below cost, with the anticipation of ongoing revenue from expensive supplies. Today, think cheap printers with expensive ink cartridges. This is another model that requires deep pockets to start, so be careful.

    If you dont like any of these models, you can always try the non-revenue model, sometimes called the Twitter model, where you count on investors to sustain your costs while your valuation increases exponentially based on millions of customers. The nonprofit version of this is a service so valuable and recognized, like UNICEF, that you never run out of donors and philanthropists.

    Yet smart people dont count on being one of these, and have a plan to validate their business model, concurrent with their plan to validate their solution. Certainly you shouldnt be afraid of using the word "profit" in your discussions with a business advisor, potential investors, partners, and even customers.

    A reasonable profit will make your idea a reality for all, rather than a dream.




What is business model in business plan?

Difference between business plan and business model. The business model is the mechanism through which the company generates its profit while the business plan is a document presenting the companys strategy and expected financial performance for the years to come.

Business Model vs. Business Plan
Business plan and business model are 2 completely different notions. Whats the difference between the 2?

Difference between business plan and business model
The business model is the mechanism through which the company generates its profit while the business plan is a document presenting the companys strategy and expected financial performance for the years to come.

    As you can see, the business model is at the center of the business plan.

    The business model describes how the company is positioned within its industrys value chain, and how it organizes its relations with its suppliers, clients, and partners in order to generate profits. The business plan translates this positioning in a series of strategic actions and quantifies their financial impact.

Examples of business models
Here are some examples of the most common business models:
 class=examples"Production
Advertising
Commission
Subscription
Freemium
Accessories

Lets dive in to these examples in greater details.

The business model of production
It is the most basic business model, the company sales the products and services it produces. In order for that business model to be viable, the company needs to generate enough sales to cover its production, distribution, and storage costs.

    The advertising business model
    Here the goal is to generate revenues by selling advertising space.
    On the Internet this model can be segmented based on the type of advertising:
 class="examples"CPM (cost per thousand): the advertiser pays the publisher a fixed amount for 1,000 impressions.
    CPC (cost per click): the advertiser pays the publisher every time someone clicks on the ad. The amount paid can be fixed or established through an auction process.
    CPA (cost per action): the advertiser pays every time a specific action is executed. An action can be a sale or a lead for example. The amount can be fixed or set as a percentage of the action value.
    This business model is already slightly more complex than the production one given that the company first need to invest in order to create a large audience before it can attract advertisers.

    Business model based on commission (or distribution)
    The company acts as an intermediary between the seller and the buyer and takes a cut of every sell it helps generate.
        This business model is generally less risky than the 2 previous ones (and therefore less profitable) as the level of investment required can be minimal.

    The subscription business model
    The company receives revenues from its subscribers at regular intervals. This business model has one clear advantage: the company knows in advance how much revenues it is going to generate. The flip side is that it often takes several months to recover the subscriber acquisition costs leading to a lower cash generation at the beginning of the cycle.

    The freemium business model
    The company offers 2 versions of its product. A free version with a limited set of features which goals are either to raise awareness about the product or to create a network effect. And a paid version, comprising more features, from which it can generate enough margin to cover the cost of the free users.
The keys to success with this business model are to be able to generate huge network effect (example: LinkedIn) and/or to convert a sufficient number of free users into paid customers (example: Uservoice).

The accessories business model
The company offers one product for free or at a price close to its production cost and generates a profit on the sale of accessories. The classic example of this business model is the sale of razor blades: razors are sold for nothing but you have to continually buy expensive blades to be able to use it.
    These lists of business models is far from being exhaustive, and if you have questions regarding a business model in particular feel free to ask it using the comment form below.


    </string>

    <string name="business_model_vrs_plan">

        Difference between business plan and business model. The business model is the mechanism through which the company generates its profit while the business plan is a document presenting the companys strategy and expected financial performance for the years to come.


  Business Model vs. Business Plan
    Business plan and business model are 2 completely different notions. Whats the difference between the 2?

    Difference between business plan and business model
   The business model is the mechanism through which the company generates its profit while the business plan is a document presenting the companys strategy and expected financial performance for the years to come.

    As you can see, the business model is at the center of the business plan.

    The business model describes how the company is positioned within its industrys value chain, and how it organizes its relations with its suppliers, clients, and partners in order to generate profits. The business plan translates this positioning in a series of strategic actions and quantifies their financial impact.

Examples of business models
Here are some examples of the most common business models:
 class="examples"Production
Advertising
Commission
Subscription
Freemium
Accessories

Lets dive in to these examples in greater details.

The business model of production
Its the most basic business model, the company sales the products and services it produces. In order for that business model to be viable, the company needs to generate enough sales to cover its production, distribution, and storage costs.

   The advertising business model
    Here the goal is to generate revenues by selling advertising space.
    On the Internet this model can be segmented based on the type of advertising
 class="examples"CPM (cost per thousand): the advertiser pays the publisher a fixed amount for 1,000 impressions.
    CPC (cost per click): the advertiser pays the publisher every time someone clicks on the ad. The amount paid can be fixed or established through an auction process.
    CPA (cost per action): the advertiser pays every time a specific action is executed. An action can be a sale or a lead for example. The amount can be fixed or set as a percentage of the action value.
    This business model is already slightly more complex than the production one given that the company first need to invest in order to create a large audience before it can attract advertisers.

    Business model based on commission (or distribution)
    The company acts as an intermediary between the seller and the buyer and takes a cut of every sell it helps generate.
        This business model is generally less risky than the 2 previous ones (and therefore less profitable) as the level of investment required can be minimal.

    The subscription business model
   The company receives revenues from its subscribers at regular intervals. This business model has one clear advantage: the company knows in advance how much revenues it is going to generate. The flip side is that it often takes several months to recover the subscriber acquisition costs leading to a lower cash generation at the beginning of the cycle.

    The freemium business model.
   The company offers 2 versions of its product. A free version with a limited set of features which goals are either to raise awareness about the product or to create a network effect. And a paid version, comprising more features, from which it can generate enough margin to cover the cost of the free users.
The keys to success with this business model are to be able to generate huge network effect (example: LinkedIn) and/or to convert a sufficient number of free users into paid customers (example: Uservoice).

The accessories business model
The company offers one product for free or at a price close to its production cost and generates a profit on the sale of accessories. The classic example of this business model is the sale of razor blades: razors are sold for nothing but you have to continually buy expensive blades to be able to use it.
    These lists of business models is far from being exhaustive, and if you have questions regarding a business model in particular feel free to ask it using the comment form below.

    </string>

    <string name="direct_marketing">
    Direct marketing is an advertising strategy that relies on the individual distribution of a sales pitch to potential customers. Mail, email, and texting are among the delivery systems used. It is called direct marketing because it generally eliminates the middleman such as advertising media.

   How Direct Marketing Works
   Unlike most marketing campaigns, direct marketing campaigns do not rely on advertising in mass media. Instead, they deliver their sales pitches by mail, by phone, or by email. Although the numbers of pitches sent can be massive, an attempt is often made to personalize the message, inserting the recipients name or city in a prominent place.


    The call to action is a common factor in much of direct marketing. The recipient of the message is urged to immediately respond by calling a toll-free phone number, sending in a reply card, or clicking on a link in an email promotion. Any response is a positive indicator of a prospective purchase. This variety of direct marketing is often called direct response marketing.
Targeting in Direct Marketing
The most effective direct marketing campaigns use lists of targeted prospects in order to send their messages only to the likeliest prospects. The lists might target families who have recently had a baby, or new homeowners, or recent retirees with products or services that they are most likely to need.

    Catalogs are a form of direct marketing with a history that dates back to the latter half of the 19th century. In modern times, catalogs are usually sent only to consumers who have indicated an interest by a previous purchase of a similar product.

The Advantages and Disadvantages of Direct Marketing
A direct marketing pitch that is delivered to the widest possible audience is probably the least effective. That is, the company may gain a few customers while merely annoying all of the other recipients. Junk mail, spam email, and texting all are forms of direct marketing that many people cant get rid of fast enough.


    Many companies engage in opt-in or permission marketing, which limits their mailing or emailing to people who have indicated a willingness to receive it. Lists of opt-in subscribers are particularly valuable as they indicate a real interest in the products or services being advertised.

Who Uses Direct Marketing
Despite its drawbacks, direct marketing has its appeal, particularly to companies on a shoestring budget who cant afford to pay for television or internet advertising campaigns.
    Direct marketing is the preferred advertising strategy for small local businesses, which can distribute hundreds of fliers, coupons, or menus for less than it would cost them to place an ad or make a commercial.

    By its nature, the effectiveness of a direct marketing campaign is easier to measure than other types of advertising. This is because they often contain a call to action. The company and measure its success by how many consumers make the call, return the card, use the coupon, or click on the link.

class="takeaways"
Key Takeaways
Direct marketing relies on distribution to individual consumers rather than advertising in mass media.
The call to action is a common factor in much of direct marketing.
The effectiveness of direct marketing is easier to measure than media advertising.


Direct marketing fundamentals
Direct marketing occurs when the “producer” connects with the end user. The end user may be a consumer or a business.

    Direct marketing applies to product and service-oriented businesses, and to nonprofit organizations. In all situations, there is no intermediary involved. Direct marketing describes this interactive communication with the end user.

    Direct marketing is not synonymous with mass marketing. The most effective direct marketing takes place when there is a clear connection to reach the target market.

    Organizations may use several ways to leverage direct marketing as they communicate with and deliver products to their customers. This may include using a direct sales force, catalogs, websites, email, direct mail, telemarketing, seminars, trade shows, and other ―one-to-one‖ techniques to communicate and sell to their customers and clients.

    Some of these direct marketing methods have grown dramatically, especially with the growth of marketing over the Internet. There is evidence that other direct marketing approaches have diminished, such as reports that the response to direct mail is often below one percent compared to the five percent+ response rate numbers more commonly experienced in the past.

 class="exception"
Companies may choose to leverage direct marketing exclusively:

Getting ready to create a marketing plan?
Get practical ideas and good models with dozens of examples of successful marketing plans with Sales and Marketing Pro.>

Finish your own Marketing Plan
Lands’ End
    Mary Kay Cosmetics
 Prepaid Legal Services

    Many local nonprofit organizations also use direct marketing exclusively.
  Nonprofit.net

    Other businesses use direct marketing in concert with other marketing channels:
  Nonprofit.net

    Many local nonprofit organizations also use direct marketing exclusively.
   Dell Computers
        NordicTrack
       Neiman Marcus

   Types of Direct Marketing
    The most common forms of direct marketing are:
      Face- to-face selling Internet marketing
        Direct mail
    Catalogs
   Telemarketing
Direct-response advertising
Kiosk marketing




Let‘s look at these in more detail:
Internet Marketing
The Internet has revolutionized direct marketing for promoting the sale of products and services to targeted audiences. Access to the Internet provides users with services in four basic areas:
i. Information
ii. Entertainment
iii. Shopping
iv. Individual and group communication

Online channels can eliminate geographic considerations. With this capability people around the world have the same access as the person across the street. Many businesses that can sell their products and services through downloading, or who can economically ship those products, have discovered an entirely new way to market.

The Internet makes direct marketing easier, more targeted, more flexible, more responsive, more affordable, and potentially more profitable than ever. Virtually every business should seriously consider the Internet as a part of their marketing mix and determine if it is a viable fit for their direct marketing efforts.



Face-to-Face Selling

The most traditional direct marketing involves the in-house sales force personally contacting potential and established consumers. Examples of organizations that use face-to-face selling include:
i. Mary Kay
ii. Avon
iii. Amway


Direct Mail
Direct mail is described as sending information about a special offer, product or sale announcement, service reminder, or some other type of communication to a person at a particular street or electronic address. Historically direct mail has existed in the form of printed materials, but CDs, audio tapes, video tapes, fax mail, email, and voice mail are also used in direct mail campaigns. For example, America Online experienced a highly successful campaign through mailing out CD-ROMs to prospective customers. Direct mail permits high target-market selectivity; it can be personalized, it is flexible, and it allows early testing and response measurement to take place. A highly selective and accurate mailing list often determines the success of direct mail efforts to enhance response rates and control costs.

Catalogs
Product catalogs are another version of direct mail where the catalogs are the communication tool. The most common use of this approach involves featuring a variety of products that target the needs of a specific audience who have shown a propensity to order from catalogs. An increasing number of business-to-business marketers are sending catalogs on CD-ROM to prospects and customers. The average U.S. household receives more than 50 catalogs each year, ranging from general merchandise to specialty goods.
Examples of general merchandise catalogs are:
i. Spiegel
ii. J.C. Penny

Examples of specialty goods catalogs are:
i. Pottery Barn
ii. PC Connection

Telemarketing
    The process of contacting people on a qualified list to sell services over the phone has grown in popularity to the point that the average household receives 19 telemarketing calls each year. Successful telemarketing campaigns depend on a good calling list, an effective script and contact structure, and well-trained people that are compensated and rewarded for making calls that result in sales. The telecommunications industry, for example, has used telemarketing extensively to attempt to increase their market share.
This includes:
i. ATT
ii. MCI WorldCom
iii. Sprint

>Direct-Response Advertising
Direct-response advertising is communicating with potential buyers through television, radio, magazines, and newspapers. The prospective consumer watches, hears, or reads about the product or service and initiates a call to a toll-free number to place their order. Television, for example, offers a wide range of exposure, from a 30-second commercial to a 60-minute infomercial.
Kiosk Marketing
Customer order machines, versus vending machines that actually provide products, are another form of direct marketing. Examples are:
i. Eddie Bauer: Stores place computer terminals to order from the entire line of products not available in the retail store.
ii. Florsheim Shoe Company Your bank‘s automatic teller machines (ATMs) placed in convenient and high traffic areas are another example of kiosk marketing. A combination of these direct marketing techniques may offer the optimal revenue generating solution


Why is direct marketing used?
Direct marketing allows you to generate a specific response from targeted groups of customers. Its a particularly useful tool for small businesses because it allows you to: focus limited resources where they are most likely to produce results. Measure the success of campaigns accurately by analyzing responses.

How effective is direct marketing?
Market on a budget. Direct marketing that is targeted to a specific audience can help you set realistic sales goals and improve sales results on a tight marketing budget. Businesses can run effective and purposeful direct marketing campaigns at a fraction of the cost of broadcast advertising.

What are the advantages of direct marketing?
Benefits of direct marketing. Some of the strengths of direct marketing include: Targeting: You can send specific messages to particular groups of customers and potential customers based on demographics and buying behavior. The more targeted your campaigns, the more successful they are likely to be.
Is direct marketing a pyramid scheme?
Pyramid schemes may offer products and services but in reality they are relying mostly on their money from the recruitment of new people into the organization. ... “Multi-level marketing is a sales strategy that some direct sales companies use in order to increase the sales of products or services.

Are billboards direct marketing?
It is not direct mail, although it uses direct mail. If direct mail is used, it has to be sharply targeted. It isnt advertising, although it uses advertising—including such media as billboards. ... Telephone selling is telemarketing; it is part of direct marketing only if a company is calling precious customers.


    What is direct marketing channel?
    Direct marketing channels are a series of marketing methods which can be used to practice direct marketing. A direct marketing channel, as the name suggests, is always direct and always puts the organization directly in contact with the customer or targeted prospect.

How do you do direct marketing?
Once youve outlined your target market, staging a direct-mail campaign has seven key steps:
1. Develop a mailing list.
2. Create a mailing piece.
3. Code your response vehicle.
4. Test the campaign.
5. Run the campaign.
6. Handle customer responses
7. Analyze the results of the campaign.
8. Envelope.

What is the difference between personal selling and direct marketing?
There is an emphasis on building up a relationship with the customer in personal selling whereas direct marketing seeks to impress upon the benefits of the offer.
Personal selling is the oldest form of selling while direct marketing is being used increasingly by small and big companies to increase their sales.

What are benefits of marketing?
Develops lasting relationships with your audience. Improves brand awareness and recognition. Creates loyalty and trust, with both your current customers and prospects. Helps you to build authority and credibility.
    What are the tools of direct marketing?
Any medium that can be used to deliver a communication to a customer can be employed in direct marketing, including:
i. Email marketing.
ii. Online tools
iii. Mobile.
iv. Telemarketing.
v. Voicemail marketing.
vi. Broadcast faxing.
vii. Couponing.
viii. Direct response marketing.
    What are the direct and indirect benefits of e marketing?
    Both direct and indirect marketing are methods to establish communication with customers. Its purpose is to press customers to buy a product or service. The marketer, because of the advantages of direct communication, has the ability to be aggressive in convincing the potential customer.

What are the various media that are used in direct marketing?
Marketing Mediums:
i. Print: Newspapers, magazines, printed telephone directories and billboards all fall within the category of print media.
ii. Radio: A broadcast medium like radio can be extremely effective in reaching a key demographic.
iii. Television.
iv. Direct Mail.
v. Telemarketing.
vi. Search Engine Marketing.
vii. Pay per click Marketing.
viii. Email Marketing.

What are telemarketing advantages and disadvantages?
    Telemarketing is a method of selling products and services over the telephone. It has both advantages and disadvantages. The advantages are it is easy to reach out to customers and it is cost effective if done successfully.

The disadvantages are that it has a bad reputation and some of the startup costs are expensive.

What is direct marketing in promotion mix?
Direct Marketing is a channel-agnostic form of advertising that allows businesses and nonprofits to communicate directly to the customer, with methods such as mobile messaging, email, interactive consumer websites, online display ads, fliers, catalog distribution, promotional letters, and outdoor advertising.

What are the tools of marketing?
Below are some marketing tools with an explanation of what they are and why businesses use them.
i. Classified adverts. Classified adverts or classified ads are useful for generating leads.
ii. Social media.
iii. Surveys.
iv. Google Analytics.
v. Direct mail.
vi. Media monitoring tools.
vii. Customer loyalty programs.
viii. Automation.

What are the five major promotion tools for marketing?
A promotional mix is an allocation of resources among five primary elements:
i. Advertising.
ii. Public relations or publicity.
iii. Sales promotion.
iv. Direct marketing.
v. Personal selling.

What programs do marketers use?
Below are 15 great marketing software’s that can help companies remain relevant and master marketing in the digital age:
1) Marketo.
2) Vocus.
3) HubSpot
4) Yesware.
5) Sailthru.
6) Optimove
7) LocalVox.
8) MailChimp.

What is the best marketing automation tool?
What are 20 best marketing automation software solutions of 2019?
i. HubSpot Marketing.
ii. SharpSpring.
iii. bpmonline marketing.
iv. LeadSquared.
v. Marketo.
vi. Oracle Eloqua.
vii. ActiveCampaign.
viii. Exponea.

How can I do free online marketing?
Here are seven ways to promote your business online that wont cost you a dime:
1. Use the three big local listing services.
2. Embrace social media.
3. Start a blog.
4. Put up multimedia on YouTube and Flicker.
5. SEO your company website
6. Press releases.
7. Join a relevant online community and contribute.


style="background: #e4e4e4; padding: 10px; text-align: center;">Join us or tell others to download POSH APP to receive more amazing information’s and guides like this and many other more. Until then, stay blessed.

    </string>


</resources>
