<resources>
    <string name="app_name">POSH APP</string>

    <!--notes-->
    <string name="definition">
        A business model in which a distributor network is needed to build the
        business. Usually such businesses are also multilevel marketing in nature in that payouts
        occur at more than one level. "\n\n"Network marketing is a type of business opportunity that is very popular with people looking
        for part-time, flexible businesses. Some of the best-known companies in America, including
        Avon, Mary Kay Cosmetics, Rain International and Tupperware, fall under the network
        marketing umbrella. "\n\n"

        Network marketing programs feature a low upfront investment-usually only a few hundred
        dollars for the purchase of a product sample kit-and the opportunity to sell a product line
        directly to friend, family and other personal contacts. Most network marketing programs also ask
        participants to recruit other sales representatives. The recruits constitute a reps downline, and
        their sales generate income for those above them in the program."\n\n"

        Things can get sticky when a network marketing network compensates participants primarily for
        recruiting others rather than for selling the companys products or services. A network marketing
        system in which most of the revenue comes from recruitment may be considered an illegal
        pyramid scheme."\n\n"

        Since network marketing programs are usually exempt from business opportunity regulation and
        arent defined as franchises under state and federal franchise laws, youll need to do your own
        investigation before investing any money."\n\n"

    </string>

    <string name="mlm_and_pyramid_schemes">
        Multilevel Marketing (MLM) and Pyramid Schemes Can Be Very Similar"\n"
        Considering a multilevel marketing opportunity (MLM)? Be careful. It may well be a
        legitimate multilevel marketing business. Or it may be a pyramid scheme - an illegal scam
        designed to steal your money. This article explains the difference between MLM and pyramid
        schemes so you can distinguish between them.

        Multilevel Marketing Can Be a Good Thing"\n"
        Multilevel marketing (MLM) is an attractive business proposition to many people. It offers the
        opportunity to become involved in a system for distributing products to consumers. Unlike the
        person starting a business from scratch, the MLM participant has the support of a direct
        selling company that supplies the products and sometimes offers training as well.

    </string>

    <string name="how_the_mlm_works">
        As a MLM consultant or contractor or distributor (different companies call them different
        things) you make your money by selling the products to other multilevel marketing participants.
        If they are not already a member of your MLM Company, you sign them up."\n\n"Besides earning money off your own sales, you also earn a percentage of the income generated
        by the distributors that you have brought into the program (these are known as your downline).
        Often there are bonuses for selling particular amounts of product or signing up a certain number
        of new members; you can earn cars and trips as well as cash. Sounds good, does not it? And being
        part of a well-run MLM business can be a lot like being a member of a large extended family.

    </string>
</resources>
